<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching on Personal website for Matt Aiello-Lammens</title>
    <link>/categories/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teaching on Personal website for Matt Aiello-Lammens</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ENS 610 - Semester Recap - Fall 2019</title>
      <link>/post/2019/12/27/ens-610-semester-recap-fall-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/12/27/ens-610-semester-recap-fall-2019/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished teaching ENS 610 Environmental Science I for the fourth time, and so it seems like a good time to reflect on the course a bit and jot down some notes for next year. As in years past, this course runs simultaneously with EP 603 Environmental Science for Policymakers.
Brief background Some of my notes on this course can be found here.
Matrials used this year Repeating what I&amp;rsquo;ve done in the past, I required Rachel Carson&amp;rsquo;s Silent Spring, coupled with peer-reviewed journal articles for the first half of the semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QUBES BLUE FMN</title>
      <link>/post/2019/12/04/qubes-blue-fmn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/12/04/qubes-blue-fmn/</guid>
      <description>This fall I participated in my second QUBES Faculty Mentoring Network, this time working along side several other educators to implement and/or develop learning modules associated with the Biodiversity Literacy in Undergraduate Education (BLUE) network. I chose to adapt an existing module to implement in my Introduction to Statistics for Life Science course, and still have intentions of creating a new module for our last week of new material coming up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting the bar and expectations of my students</title>
      <link>/post/2016/03/31/setting-the-bar-and-expectations-of-my-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016/03/31/setting-the-bar-and-expectations-of-my-students/</guid>
      <description>I like to think that I have high expectations of my students. Admittedly, being a novice teacher, I&amp;rsquo;m open to the idea that I&amp;rsquo;ll find out the truth after a few more years. Regardless, in my mind setting a high bar for what my students should learn and understand, and having high expectations of them, have been synonymous. Over the course of the year, I&amp;rsquo;ve begun to question this. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example - at the beginning of this semester I set out to teach my biostatistics course in much the same way that it was taught to me (and that I later helped TA) at grad school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does e-grading lead to less student engagement with feedback?</title>
      <link>/post/2016/02/25/does-e-grading-lead-to-less-student-engagement-with-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016/02/25/does-e-grading-lead-to-less-student-engagement-with-feedback/</guid>
      <description>For one of my courses this semester I&amp;rsquo;m using Blackboard Grade Center to have students submit their assignments and for me to assess them. I actually prefer to assess/correct assignments with old-fashioned pen and paper; I think it&amp;rsquo;s a bit quicker. But every semester I&amp;rsquo;m faced with a pile of correcting, whether electronic or physical, I try to start by using e-grading. One thing I&amp;rsquo;m noticing is that my students don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily seem too engaged with my feedback I&amp;rsquo;ve provided through the Grade Center.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>