<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Personal website for Matt Aiello-Lammens</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Personal website for Matt Aiello-Lammens</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ENS 610 - Semester Recap - Fall 2019</title>
      <link>/post/2019/12/27/ens-610-semester-recap-fall-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/12/27/ens-610-semester-recap-fall-2019/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished teaching ENS 610 Environmental Science I for the fourth time, and so it seems like a good time to reflect on the course a bit and jot down some notes for next year. As in years past, this course runs simultaneously with EP 603 Environmental Science for Policymakers.
Brief background Some of my notes on this course can be found here.
Matrials used this year Repeating what I&amp;rsquo;ve done in the past, I required Rachel Carson&amp;rsquo;s Silent Spring, coupled with peer-reviewed journal articles for the first half of the semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QUBES BLUE FMN</title>
      <link>/post/2019/12/04/qubes-blue-fmn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/12/04/qubes-blue-fmn/</guid>
      <description>This fall I participated in my second QUBES Faculty Mentoring Network, this time working along side several other educators to implement and/or develop learning modules associated with the Biodiversity Literacy in Undergraduate Education (BLUE) network. I chose to adapt an existing module to implement in my Introduction to Statistics for Life Science course, and still have intentions of creating a new module for our last week of new material coming up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on the 2016 North American Congress for Conservation Biology</title>
      <link>/post/2016/08/03/thoughts-on-the-2016-north-american-congress-for-conservation-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016/08/03/thoughts-on-the-2016-north-american-congress-for-conservation-biology/</guid>
      <description>I started graduate school in 2007 with the intention of becoming a conservation biologist. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I had a good sense for what that meant at the time, given my lack of experience, but I knew that I wanted to work toward science that protected natural places and the organisms in them. So, it seemed logical that the first scientific meeting I would attend would be the Congress for Conservation Biology - the 2008 international meeting in Chattanooga to be exact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting the bar and expectations of my students</title>
      <link>/post/2016/03/31/setting-the-bar-and-expectations-of-my-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016/03/31/setting-the-bar-and-expectations-of-my-students/</guid>
      <description>I like to think that I have high expectations of my students. Admittedly, being a novice teacher, I&amp;rsquo;m open to the idea that I&amp;rsquo;ll find out the truth after a few more years. Regardless, in my mind setting a high bar for what my students should learn and understand, and having high expectations of them, have been synonymous. Over the course of the year, I&amp;rsquo;ve begun to question this. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example - at the beginning of this semester I set out to teach my biostatistics course in much the same way that it was taught to me (and that I later helped TA) at grad school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does e-grading lead to less student engagement with feedback?</title>
      <link>/post/2016/02/25/does-e-grading-lead-to-less-student-engagement-with-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016/02/25/does-e-grading-lead-to-less-student-engagement-with-feedback/</guid>
      <description>For one of my courses this semester I&amp;rsquo;m using Blackboard Grade Center to have students submit their assignments and for me to assess them. I actually prefer to assess/correct assignments with old-fashioned pen and paper; I think it&amp;rsquo;s a bit quicker. But every semester I&amp;rsquo;m faced with a pile of correcting, whether electronic or physical, I try to start by using e-grading. One thing I&amp;rsquo;m noticing is that my students don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily seem too engaged with my feedback I&amp;rsquo;ve provided through the Grade Center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYBG native plant symposium</title>
      <link>/post/2015/10/05/nybg-native-plant-symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015/10/05/nybg-native-plant-symposium/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I went to the New York Botanical Garden for the Native Plant Symposium. Overall, it was a good experience. The organizers put together a great line-up of speakers, and I thought each presentation was interesting and thought provoking. One aspect of this symposium that was interesting to me was that it was targeted towards a fairly general audience. The talks were not like those you would see at ESA, though in a few cases new research was presented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>South Africa 2015</title>
      <link>/post/2015/08/18/south-africa-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015/08/18/south-africa-2015/</guid>
      <description>A little less than a month ago, I took my second trip to South Africa. Last year I spent nearly seven weeks there, collecting field data that we&amp;rsquo;re currently in the process of analyzing. It was an amazing experience, and given the length of time I was there, I felt like I was pretty immersed in the region. In contrast, this year I was in country for only seven days - two teaching a Software Carpentry workshop, one playing tourist, and three at a symposium our research group organized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring time naturalizing</title>
      <link>/post/2015/06/04/spring-time-naturalizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015/06/04/spring-time-naturalizing/</guid>
      <description>Every year, when spring comes, I get pretty excited to get outside and do some naturalizing. Well, mostly botanizing. I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself a particularly good naturalist. I can&amp;rsquo;t walk through the forests close to home and spout off the names of all the plants around me - common or binomial. I can name the most prominent ones. I can usually identify the habitat I&amp;rsquo;m in. But overall, I have a lot improving to do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>